ELIZABETH C. MANGANO

Huntersville, NC

(513) 646-3493 • emangano2816@gmail.com LinkedIn • GitHub • Portfolio

Experienced business analyst and testing specialist eager to utilize my Certificate in Coding: Full Stack Web Development from the University of North Carolina at Charlotte to build user-friendly, efficient, responsive, mobile-first web applications. My attention to detail, strong organization and problem-solving abilities, and dogged determination have consistently enabled me to provide clients with deliverables that are timely, accurate, polished, and of the highest quality.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages	HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, SQL
Other	Third-party APIs, GitHub, Git, Node.js
Software	Visual Studio, SAS, SharePoint, Bugzilla, MS Access, Excel, Word, Visio,
	Outlook, PowerPoint, SnagIt, Adobe, SQL Developer, and IBM Cognos Analytics.

CODING PROFILE

MOVIE-DRINK MATCHMAKER

Technologies: HTML, CSS, Bulma CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Third-party APIs, moment.js

Worked collaboratively with 4 peers to develop a responsive, mobile-first Movie-Drink Matchmaker application. The user selects a movie genre and drink type and the application returns movies and drinks meeting the criteria. The user is able to scroll through suggested movies and drinks until finding a favorite combination. The favorite combination is saved to local storage and persists on the favorites page of the application.

JAVASCRIPT CODE QUIZ

Technologies: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Local Storage

The Code Quiz tests a user's JavaScript knowledge. The user has 30 seconds to answer 10 questions. Each correct answer earns 5 points. Each incorrect answer deducts 10 seconds from the timer. When time is up or all questions have been answered the user is able to save their score and initials to the high scores page of the application.

WEATHER DASHBOARD

Technologies: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, moment.js, Third-party APIs

The Weather Dashboard application takes in a user specified city and return the current and 5-day forecast for that city. The searched cities are "pinned" to the application for reference. Clicking on the "pinned" cities retrieves the forecast as before.

ELIZABETH C. MANGANO

Huntersville, NC (513) 646-3493 • emangano2816@gmail.com

<u>LinkedIn</u> • <u>GitHub</u> • <u>Portfolio</u>

RELATED PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ITS CONSULTING, Lutherville, MD Business Analyst/Testing Specialist, GANTECH Business Analyst, Computer Aid Inc Business Analyst, Deloitte & Touche LLP **2011 – Present** 2012 - Present 2012 2011 – 2012

Provide functional support for the Maryland State Department of Education (MSDE) Longitudinal Data Feeder System Maintenance and Support contract. Serve as liaison between development team and MSDE end users. Log and review support requests to determine defect type and severity. Replicate defects in test region. Work with development team to produce business solution strategies to meet client's needs.

- Verify accuracy and integrity of resolved defects prior to client's UAT.
- Create and maintain use case scenarios and system test plans.
- Redesign process flows, application designs, and file formats to meet client's needs.
- Perform gap analysis on module modification.
- Communicate business solutions to development team and client using proto-types.

MARYLAND STATE DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION (MSDE), Baltimore, MD Education Program Specialist, Division of Accountability and Assessment

2008-2011

Created SAS programs to process, validate, and compare data from twenty-five agencies on an annual basis. Worked and collaborated with Oracle developers to manage and update annually the student discipline data collection apparatus. Experienced at identifying and resolving program bugs. Dedicated to improving process flow, ensuring data quality, enhancing product functionality, and satisfying business needs.

• Developed SAS programs to replicate application processes in order to validate calculations.

EDUCATION

UNIVERISTY OF NORTH CAROLINA at CHARLOTTE, Charlotte, NC

Coding: Full Stack Web Development Certificate

Expected: 10/2021

OHIO STATE UNIVERSITY, Columbus, OH

Master of Applied Statistics

OHIO UNIVERSITY, Athens, OH

Bachelor of Science in Education, Summa Cum Laude